Gabriel Diegel

Email: gabriel.diegel@icloud.com Github: https://github.com/gdiegel

Professional Summary

Creative Software Engineer with 15 years of demonstrated experience in Software Engineering, Solutions Architecture, and Technology Leadership. Deep expertise in Distributed Systems, Microservices, Event-Driven Architecture, and Continuous Delivery. Highly motivated self-starter with a winning mindset and a bias for action.

Currently

Staff Software Engineer at Nearsure in Lima, Peru

Programming languages

Java, Go, Kotlin, Python

Technologies

Spring Boot, WebFlux, Quarkus, Echo, Docker, Kubernetes, Git, PostgreSQL, MySQL, Pub/Sub, Maven, Gradle, Google Cloud Platform, AWS, Terraform, Datadog, Elasticsearch

Experience

2024-current	Staff Software Engineer at Nearsure in Lima, Peru
2023-2024	Senior Software Engineer at Nearsure in Lima, Peru
2019-2022	Senior Software Engineer at Tekton in Lima, Peru
2018-2019	Senior Software Development Engineer in Test at 1&1 Internet SE in Karlsruhe, Germany
2013-2018	Test Software Development Engineer in Test at 1&1 Internet SE in Karlsruhe, Germany
2010-2012	Analyst at Atos Worldline GmbH in Frankfurt, Germany
2009-2010	Software Engineer at Fraunhofer Institute for Physical Measurement Techniques IPM in Freiburg, Germany

Education

B.Sc. in Psychology at Universität Hagen, Germany
Dipl.-Ing. (FH) in Electrical Engineering at Hochschule Karlsruhe, Germany

Thesis: "Development of an automated image analysis software for a fluorescence-based data acquisition system for the detection of airborne microorganisms"

Projects

2016 retryJ: A retry library for Java

Languages

German: Native, English: Fluent, Spanish: Fluent, Italian: Learning

Articles

2015	"Take your testing DSL to the next level with custom assertions"
2016	"JUnit5-Feeble screams from forests well known"
2017	"Using neo-problem with a pure Spring Boot service"
2018	"Writing a custom test engine with Kotlin"
2019	"Automated acceptance testing"
2019	"Running acceptance tests on GitlabCI"